avazu.net 2019-12-11

# Opt Out

##### Overview

The following describes the overall company Privacy Policy of Avazu (referred to below "Avazu", "we", "us" and "our"). We understand how important it is to keep your personal information confidential, and discrete, especially in today's online world. The importance of your privacy is outlined in detail below. This Privacy Policy was created to inform you what information we collect when you interact with our customer’s (“Advertisers”) websites or apps that uses the Avazu Services; as well as how that information is collected and used by companies that display advertisements("Partners"). The potential customers who visit Advertisers' websites that employ our services are referred to as "Prospects" throughout this document. Because our Privacy Policy may be updated periodically, it is imperative that this document is read thoroughly and often.

##### Personal and Non-Personal Information

Personally Related Information ("PRI") is data about you that is personally identifiable; this is generally described as your name, email address, credit card number and/or any other information that might be considered private. The PRI that Avazu collects from you is information you supply to us; such as your name, email address, credit card number and Avazu account login. That information is maintained by Avazu only so that you do not have to enter it each time you visit our website to login to your account.

Non-Personally Related Information ("NPRI") data is gathered by Avazu and Avazu's Partners, so it can be used by Avazu for the purpose of online Retargeting only. NPRI data collected by Avazu for advertising purposes is completely anonymous, and only includes the following information:

  * Information about your device, such as the type and model, manufacturer, operating system (e.g. iOS or Android), carrier name, IP address, mobile browser (e.g. Chrome, Safari), applications using the Avazu Services and the version of such applications, and identifiers assigned to your device, such as its iOS Identifier for Advertising (IDFA), Android Advertising ID, or unique device identifier (a number uniquely allocated to your device by your device manufacturer).
  * Log information, including the app or website visited, session start/stop time, time zone, and network connection type (e.g., WiFi, cellular), and cookie information.
  * The geo-location of your device (using GPS or other geo-location data), when location services have been enabled for the mobile app or website that uses the Avazu Services.
  * Information about ads served, viewed, or clicked on, such as the type of ad, where the ad was served, whether you clicked on it, and whether you visited the advertiser’s website or purchased the product or service advertised.
  * Information that Avazu Customers and other third parties have collected and shared with Avazu, such as information about activity in their services. This may include the content you view or searches you made, the language you prefer, or other non-personally identifying demographic or interest information, to help make the ads served to you more relevant.

None of this information, under any circumstances, individually or grouped together, can be traced back to a specific individual.

##### Cookies

To those unfamiliar, a cookie is used to store data on a computer's hard drive. In today's online world all websites and applications utilize cookies to one extent or another. Avazu uses it's cookies to provide a Re-targeting service only. A Prospect receives a cookie when interacting with Avazu.net and /or our customer’s (“Advertisers”) or Partner’s websites or apps that uses the Avazu Services; Part of Avazu's business requires that Avazu has no access to, or control over Partners’ cookies. However, requires that each Partner only collect NPRI information for the use of serving retargeted ads. Any Partner found in violation of this policy will be immediately removed.

##### Avazu's Guidelines for the Use of Cookies and NPRI

Avazu's technology requires the use of cookies so we can promptly deliver advertisements to our Advertiser's Prospects on our Partner's sites or apps. This form of marketing is designated as Retargeting; this enhances an Advertiser's potential revenue by specifically re-targeting those whom are interested in the products. When a Prospect visits one of Avazu's Advertiser's websites, an Avazu pixel on that site sets an Avazu cookie on the browser of the Prospect. Therefore after the cookie is planted when a Prospect visits one of Avazu's Partners' websites; our Partner's website will identify the cookie on browser of the Prospect and recognize that they previously visited our Advertiser's website.

The Prospect will then be shown an advertisement from that Advertiser. In this instance, Avazu will know that the Prospect first visited our Advertiser's website, and then our Partner's website. This information is all that is used in reporting our Prospects to advertisers and therefore in no way can be used to specifically identify an individual.

The NPRI data collected by Avazu in the above outlined process of Retargeting will be kept by Avazu's database for the period of one year only. After one year all data is routinely destroyed. This information is only used for the purpose of re-targeting and in no way is personal information. You may Opt-Out of Avazu's services with ease by following the instructions listed below.

##### How to Opt-Out of Avazu's Services

Opting Out of Avazu's services is easy; however please note that by Opting-Out, you will not be able to take full advantage of Retargeted advertising or have your Avazu account login information remembered for you. By deleting your cookies, you will disable Avazu as well as its Partners ability to deliver ads. However, you must ensure you clear your cookies each time you interact with Avazu or one of our Advertiser's websites to ensure you are not receiving Retargeted advertisements.

##### IP's

An Internet Protocol (IP) address is automatically assigned to your computer or mobile device every time you establish a connection on the Internet. Avazu will use your IP address only to assess problems with the server.

##### Your Account

Avazu will only access your information if when you become an advertiser with Avazu, provide comments, submit a problem, or request information from Avazu and provide your name or return contact information. Contact information provided in connection with problems, comments or requests is used only to respond to those problems, comments or requests.

##### Security

At Avazu, the security of your information is our utmost priority, and we take many strict measures in order to protect our data from unauthorized access, and unauthorized disclosure or destruction of data. Our data is only stored in centers that provide the highest quality security for your information. Physical access is strictly controlled both at the perimeter and at building ingress points by professional security staff utilizing video surveillance, state of the art intrusion detection systems, and other electronic means.

##### Removing Your Account Information From Our Records

You may e-mail us at Avazu.net to remove your contact information from our database assuming there are no current pending transactions.

##### Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

##### Personal Information

Avazu will not sell, trade, release or use your information in any way that is not strictly outlined in the above document.

##### Transactional Information

Avazu 's gathered information such as traffic patterns, sales, aggregate data regarding general shopping patterns, and any other information will only be shared with reputable individuals. This data will never contain any Personal information of the users however.

##### Legal Issues

Avazu discloses personal information when required by law, judicial process, warrant, subpoena or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary for the following:

To conform to the edict of the law or comply with a legal process served on Avazu or its Website or Services. To protect and defend the property rights of Avazu, the Avazu Website, or that of Avazu Users or to act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Avazu Users, employees, or the general public.

##### Other Sites' Policies

Avazu has no direct control over, nor does it bear any of the responsibility for the privacy policies and/or content of any sites or advertisers linked to or on Avazu Services, or the data these sites might deposit on your hard drive.

##### Your Consent Choice & Contacting Us

For mobile devices, your iOS mobile device may provide a “Limit Ad Tracking” setting. On Android devices, your settings may allow you to “Opt out of Interest-Based Ads.” When you have opted out using this setting on a device, Avazu will not use in-app information collected from that device to infer your interests or serve ads to that device that are targeted based on your inferred interests. Your mobile web browser may also provide a “Do Not Track” browser setting. When you have enabled this setting in your browser, Avazu will not use mobile web browsing information from that browser to infer your interests or serve ads to that device that are targeting based on your inferred interests. Avazu requires its advertising customers to honor opt-out preferences expressed using these controls.

By visiting the Avazu website, you consent to the collection, use and distribution of any personalized data as outlined above. If there are any changes to the policy statement you will be notified before the continued use of our technology. Although we may alter the privacy policy at any time if any changes are made you will be notified via email as soon as the adjustment is made.
